<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[29th Annual Couchiching Conference, 1960]]></title><description><![CDATA[The 1960 Couchiching Conference, a summer symposium on national and international affairs put together by the Canadian Institute on Public Affairs and the Canadian Broadcasting Corporation, assembles for its 29th annual meeting. The theme of the 1960 conference was "The Latin Americas."Every night at this time for the next week we're going to hear speakers from various Latin American countries—statesmen, scholars, businessmen—to talk among themselves and with colleagues from the United States, Great Britain, and Canada about the problems facing their various countries and in particular how these problems can affect Canadians. During the week we'll have first hand reports on the political upheavals which have occurred in the south and the enormous social and economic revolutions which are now in progress.<br /><br />An online collection of early educational public radio content from the National Association of Educational Broadcasters (NAEB).]]></description><link>https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/programs/29th-annual-couchiching-conference-1960/</link><image><url>https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/images/podcast.png</url><title>29th Annual Couchiching Conference, 1960</title><link>https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/programs/29th-annual-couchiching-conference-1960/</link></image><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 17:35:36 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/rss/29th-annual-couchiching-conference-1960.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><managingEditor><![CDATA[National Association of Educational Broadcasters]]></managingEditor><item><title><![CDATA[Latin America: Power relationships in the Americas]]></title><description><![CDATA[One question has been raised touched upon but never fully developed: the pressures and tugs of the big powers and the effects they produce in the different Latin American countries. The biggest power today is the United States, and this name has been invoked frequently during the past week with different degrees of emphasis. But another power has greatly influenced Latin America in the past and still has strong links with it today: the United Kingdom. This program features remarks by Roy Rubottom representing the United States and J.C.J. Metford representing the United Kingdom.]]></description><link>https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-m03xxq1w/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-m03xxq1w/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 1960 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://mith-uta.s3.amazonaws.com/data/audio/cpb-aacip-500-m03xxq1w.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mp3"/><dc:creator>Wilson, Bob</dc:creator><dc:subject>World Politics</dc:subject></item><item><title><![CDATA[Latin America: Revolution]]></title><description><![CDATA[The third session of the conference features a speech by Dora Vasconcellos, known for his writings in Cuban and U.S. history and relations and as director of the Cuban-American Cultural Institute of Havana, a self-imposed Cuban exile.]]></description><link>https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-m32nb072/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-m32nb072/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 1960 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://mith-uta.s3.amazonaws.com/data/audio/cpb-aacip-500-m32nb072.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mp3"/><dc:creator>Wilson, Bob</dc:creator><dc:subject>Writing</dc:subject></item><item><title><![CDATA[Latin America: Economic development and expansion]]></title><description><![CDATA[Issues of economic development and expansion are remarkably similar in both Latin America and Canada. For example, how to attract foreign capital without incurring the disadvantages of foreign ownership or foreign debt and how to expand without inflation. This session features speeches by economist Dr. Victor Urquidi, economic geographer Paul Bouchard, and former Costa Rican president José Figueres Ferrer.]]></description><link>https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-0p0wtn57/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-0p0wtn57/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 1960 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://mith-uta.s3.amazonaws.com/data/audio/cpb-aacip-500-0p0wtn57.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mp3"/><dc:creator>Wilson, Bob</dc:creator><dc:subject>World Politics</dc:subject></item><item><title><![CDATA[Latin America: Canada relationships with Latin America]]></title><description><![CDATA[This final session of the 1960 Couchaching Conference addresses the questions: why should Canada be interested in the Latin Americas at all, and, more particularly, should Canada join the Organization of American States? Speakers include Charles G. Fenwick, director of the Department of International Law at the Pan American Union; A. J. Knowles, who worked for the Royal Bank of Canada in Latin America for 28 years; and Professor Marcel Roussin, who recently wrote a book on Canada and the inter-American system.

]]></description><link>https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-1v5bh263/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-1v5bh263/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 1960 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://mith-uta.s3.amazonaws.com/data/audio/cpb-aacip-500-1v5bh263.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mp3"/><dc:creator>Wilson, Bob</dc:creator><dc:subject>World Politics</dc:subject></item><item><title><![CDATA[Latin America: Opening session]]></title><description><![CDATA[The opening session features a speech by Dr. José Figueres Ferrer, a two-time president of Costa Rica and major figure in the liberal revolution in Latin America.]]></description><link>https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-930nwz5m/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-930nwz5m/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 1960 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://mith-uta.s3.amazonaws.com/data/audio/cpb-aacip-500-930nwz5m.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mp3"/><dc:creator>Wilson, Bob</dc:creator><dc:subject>World Politics</dc:subject></item><item><title><![CDATA[Latin America: Texture of life in Latin America]]></title><description><![CDATA[Tonight we're going to try to feel the texture of life in the southern hemisphere to trace the multicolored patterns blending the fabric which is the Latin American way of life. We should talk of the Spanish heritage, the role of the church, the tensions created by the extreme wealth and extreme poverty and the racial intermingling in the different countries which form what we in the north call Latin America.]]></description><link>https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-dv1cpv6t/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-dv1cpv6t/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 1960 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://mith-uta.s3.amazonaws.com/data/audio/cpb-aacip-500-dv1cpv6t.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mp3"/><dc:creator>Wilson, Bob</dc:creator><dc:subject>World Politics</dc:subject></item></channel></rss>