<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[America Street, U.S.A.]]></title><description><![CDATA[In the city of Sunnyvale California, there is a street named America street. Families of many different backgrounds live on the street and in the immediate neighborhood. It's a melting pot of America in miniature. What are the feelings, the attitudes, the texture of life on America Street? What do these Americans think about America as it is today? For if we are to approach the reality of the American experiment in democracy we must know, understand, and respond to the opinions of America Street. We ask you to imagine that you are overhearing a discussion among the residents of America Street as occasionally compared and contrasted with an informed opinion from other sources.<br /><br />An online collection of early educational public radio content from the National Association of Educational Broadcasters (NAEB).]]></description><link>https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/programs/america-street-usa/</link><image><url>https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/images/podcast.png</url><title>America Street, U.S.A.</title><link>https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/programs/america-street-usa/</link></image><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 17:35:36 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/rss/america-street-usa.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><managingEditor><![CDATA[National Association of Educational Broadcasters]]></managingEditor><item><title><![CDATA[#4 Controversial issues in education sex education and busing]]></title><description><![CDATA[Today's topic: controversial issues in American education. Our questions concern two current educational issues: sex education and the bussing of school children to alleviate racial discrimination. We discovered that opinions on these issues were based on a fundamental and continuing conflict in American society the conflict between individual rights and generally agreed upon social values. For example, while all of our respondents agreed that ignorance about sex could be harmful to young people, there was disagreement about how children should be instructed and the rights of parents to determine what their children learn.]]></description><link>https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-x63b4b50/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-x63b4b50/</guid><enclosure url="https://mith-uta.s3.amazonaws.com/data/audio/cpb-aacip-500-x63b4b50.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mp3"/><dc:creator>National Educational Radio Network</dc:creator><dc:subject>Youth</dc:subject></item><item><title><![CDATA[#8 T.V.]]></title><description><![CDATA[Today's topic: television in America. Our questions on the topic television in America focused on two points of current and controversial all interest. Does TV portray an accurate picture of life in America, and what about violence on TV? Perhaps in a more general sense our question was: what role does TV play in the lives of Americans today?]]></description><link>https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-pc2t8m19/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-pc2t8m19/</guid><enclosure url="https://mith-uta.s3.amazonaws.com/data/audio/cpb-aacip-500-pc2t8m19.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mp3"/><dc:creator>National Educational Radio Network</dc:creator><dc:subject>Violence</dc:subject></item><item><title><![CDATA[#5 Crime and police in America]]></title><description><![CDATA[Current statistics indicate that crime rates are rising in America. While there may be some controversy about the exact meaning of crime rate statistics, there can be no doubt of that. Criminal behavior is a serious problem. We asked several questions about the meaning of criminal behavior in America. Does it for example indicate a decline in moral values as well as the obvious question what should be done about it? We also asked some questions about our first line of defense against criminal behavior of the police. Are they doing their job or, on the other hand, do the police themselves sometimes misbehaver example by engaging in harassment of citizens?]]></description><link>https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-v97zqx7z/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-v97zqx7z/</guid><enclosure url="https://mith-uta.s3.amazonaws.com/data/audio/cpb-aacip-500-v97zqx7z.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mp3"/><dc:creator>National Educational Radio Network</dc:creator><dc:subject>Sunnyvale (Calif.)</dc:subject></item><item><title><![CDATA[#3 Generation Gap]]></title><description><![CDATA[Do the current differences between the generations indicate a significant change in the direction and values of America. Is the older generation failing to pass on the important values to the younger? What kind of discipline should be taught? Is the affluent society somehow corrupting the youth or has the older generation created a world which the younger generation for good reason finds intolerable.]]></description><link>https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-c24qpq4k/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-c24qpq4k/</guid><enclosure url="https://mith-uta.s3.amazonaws.com/data/audio/cpb-aacip-500-c24qpq4k.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mp3"/><dc:creator>National Educational Radio Network</dc:creator><dc:subject>Sunnyvale (Calif.)</dc:subject></item><item><title><![CDATA[#7 Thoughts on Viet Nam]]></title><description><![CDATA[Today's topic: the war in Vietnam. The war in Vietnam has occasioned the greatest division in America since the Civil War. The public debate in the past few years has reached every citizen as participant or observer. For today's program, further expression of public statements would be superfluous. Today we focus entirely on the opinions of America Street. America's most immediate dilemma, touching the lives and souls of every American: What do we do about the war in Vietnam?]]></description><link>https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-736m473d/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-736m473d/</guid><enclosure url="https://mith-uta.s3.amazonaws.com/data/audio/cpb-aacip-500-736m473d.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mp3"/><dc:creator>National Educational Radio Network</dc:creator><dc:subject>War &amp; Civil Defense</dc:subject></item><item><title><![CDATA[#1]]></title><description><![CDATA[Today's topic: does the average citizen have a voice in his government, and as a case study, the trip to the moon. Was it worth the money?]]></description><link>https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-td9n7c1x/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-td9n7c1x/</guid><enclosure url="https://mith-uta.s3.amazonaws.com/data/audio/cpb-aacip-500-td9n7c1x.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mp3"/><dc:creator>National Educational Radio Network</dc:creator><dc:subject>U.S. Politics</dc:subject></item><item><title><![CDATA[#9 Our opinions on America Street]]></title><description><![CDATA[An interview with Jeff Osborne and Rob Wheeler on their experience soliciting public opinions for the America Street series.]]></description><link>https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-tt4fsg60/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-tt4fsg60/</guid><enclosure url="https://mith-uta.s3.amazonaws.com/data/audio/cpb-aacip-500-tt4fsg60.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mp3"/><dc:creator>National Educational Radio Network</dc:creator><dc:subject>War &amp; Civil Defense</dc:subject></item><item><title><![CDATA[#6 Civil rights and civil disturbances]]></title><description><![CDATA[Today's topic: civil rights and civil disturbances in America. We chose America Street because in many ways it is a typical American neighborhood, but in one sense it is too typical: there are no black American families Today's topic: civil rights and civil disturbances in America. We chose America Street because in many ways it is a typical American neighborhood, but in one sense it is too typical: there are no black American families living on America Street. A few black Americans live in the surrounding neighborhoods but many if not most black residents of the county live in such ghetto areas as East Palo Alto. It might surprise some of our listeners to learn that there are ghettos in the suburbs as well as the big cities. And yet at the core of America's racial problems is the fact that for too long we have not properly taken into account of the opinions of black Americans. The black experience is foreign to most white Americans. Therefore as part of today's program we have chosen excerpts from statements by two of the most articulate spokesmen for black Americans: novelist, essayist, and playwright James Baldwin, known for his understanding and compassionate view of the black experience in America as well as the vigor of his statements, and Stokely Carmichael, an intellectual leader for black militants and activists.]]></description><link>https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-ms3k219k/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-ms3k219k/</guid><enclosure url="https://mith-uta.s3.amazonaws.com/data/audio/cpb-aacip-500-ms3k219k.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mp3"/><dc:creator>National Educational Radio Network</dc:creator><dc:subject>U.S. Politics</dc:subject></item><item><title><![CDATA[#2 Drugs in America]]></title><description><![CDATA[Today's topic: drugs in America. In the past few years there has been a great increase in the use of certain drugs, most notably marijuana, and especially among young people. More recently along with increased usage we have seen a change of attitude toward marijuana among some authorities, political as well as medical. While the subject of drug use certainly has its frightening and confusing aspects, we found that the opinions of America Street were relatively calm and objective. We also found that many of the residents of America street agreed at least in part with the opinions of the expert whom we asked to contribute to this program: Joel Fort, M.D. Dr. Fort  is the author of the book The Pleasure Seekers: The Drug Crisis, Youth, and Society, published by Bobbs-Merrill in 1969. Dr. Fort is a professor at the School of Social Welfare, University of California Berkeley and the organizer of the Center for the Solution of Special Social and Health problems in San Francisco.]]></description><link>https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-p843w92w/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-p843w92w/</guid><enclosure url="https://mith-uta.s3.amazonaws.com/data/audio/cpb-aacip-500-p843w92w.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mp3"/><dc:creator>National Educational Radio Network</dc:creator><dc:subject>Youth</dc:subject></item></channel></rss>