<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Lincoln as a social prophet]]></title><description><![CDATA[A series of readings from letters and speeches by Abraham Lincoln, prepared and delivered by Marvin Ceynar, speech instructor at Northern Illinois University.<br /><br />An online collection of early educational public radio content from the National Association of Educational Broadcasters (NAEB).]]></description><link>https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/programs/lincoln-as-a-social-prophet/</link><image><url>https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/images/podcast.png</url><title>Lincoln as a social prophet</title><link>https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/programs/lincoln-as-a-social-prophet/</link></image><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 17:35:36 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/rss/lincoln-as-a-social-prophet.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><managingEditor><![CDATA[National Association of Educational Broadcasters]]></managingEditor><item><title><![CDATA[Freedom Fighter, 1858]]></title><description><![CDATA[Episode 4: Some of us may have the belief that Abraham Lincoln hardly could have been a freedom fighter. Certainly he was not the type of activist we associate today with the word “freedom fighter.” Nevertheless, in a most profound way, the rights of all men everywhere was an idea he warmly nurtured. Lincoln delivered at least three addresses in 1858 on what is often called “the house divided issue,” that is, our nation could not exist long being half slave and half free. This program features his July 17th speech at the Springfield Illinois statehouse.]]></description><link>https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-69700x5b/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-69700x5b/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 1968 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://mith-uta.s3.amazonaws.com/data/audio/cpb-aacip-500-69700x5b.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mp3"/><dc:creator>Northern Illinois University</dc:creator><dc:subject>United States--Politics and government--20th century</dc:subject></item><item><title><![CDATA[What Place Violence in a Democracy?]]></title><description><![CDATA[Episode 1: A presentation of Abraham Lincoln’s 1838 speech decrying mob violence to the Young Men’s Lyceum in January, 1838, after the recent murder of abolitionist newspaper editor Elijah Lovejoy.]]></description><link>https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-g15tc84w/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-g15tc84w/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 1968 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://mith-uta.s3.amazonaws.com/data/audio/cpb-aacip-500-g15tc84w.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mp3"/><dc:creator>Northern Illinois University</dc:creator><dc:subject>Violence</dc:subject></item><item><title><![CDATA[Encounter with Dram, Dram Dealers]]></title><description><![CDATA[Episode 2: Six years after Abraham Lincoln made his speech to the Young Men's Lyceum in Springfield, Illinois, on the urgent need to rule out most violence and democracy, he spoke with similar force during his amazingly contemporary temperance address before the Springfield Washington Temperance Society on February 22nd, 1842. At that time, DRAM was a synonym for "liquor."]]></description><link>https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-dz033403/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-dz033403/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 1968 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://mith-uta.s3.amazonaws.com/data/audio/cpb-aacip-500-dz033403.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mp3"/><dc:creator>Northern Illinois University</dc:creator><dc:subject>United States--History--19th century</dc:subject></item><item><title><![CDATA[Words to a Divided Nation]]></title><description><![CDATA[Episode 7: This program considered several of Abraham Lincoln's speeches from 1861, including his inaugural address and a conciliatory speech delivered less than two weeks earlier on February 22nd at Philadelphia’s Independence Hall, in the face of a divided nation and the secession of seven southern states.]]></description><link>https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-5h7bwp0x/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-5h7bwp0x/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 1968 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://mith-uta.s3.amazonaws.com/data/audio/cpb-aacip-500-5h7bwp0x.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mp3"/><dc:creator>Northern Illinois University</dc:creator><dc:subject>United States--Politics and government--20th century</dc:subject></item><item><title><![CDATA[Lincoln's War...and Ours]]></title><description><![CDATA[Episode 8: Although Abraham Lincoln dealt primarily with a domestic foe in the Civil War, we wonder if he might not have some words of wisdom for us in our wars. This episode features Lincoln's remarks on four still-contemporary issues: the U.S. involvement with foreign powers; the freedom of American citizens within our own country, the actual reason why we are in a war, and the binding of up the wounds after the war is over.]]></description><link>https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-wh2ddb0x/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-wh2ddb0x/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 1968 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://mith-uta.s3.amazonaws.com/data/audio/cpb-aacip-500-wh2ddb0x.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mp3"/><dc:creator>Northern Illinois University</dc:creator><dc:subject>United States--Politics and government--20th century</dc:subject></item><item><title><![CDATA[Freedom Fighter, 1863]]></title><description><![CDATA[Episode 6: The road to complete emancipation of American Negroes is a long road. The emancipation proclamation of 1863 was a major step on that road as was the 13th Amendment of 1865. To better understand Lincoln's role in freeing the slaves., it is wise to return to procedure certainly will help us at least to understand why Lincoln so slowly initiated emancipation. One of the best explanations for his caution was his reply to a large group of Christians of all denominations. They had publicly met on September 7th, 1862 in Brian Hall, Chicago, and had adopted a memorial favoring national emancipation. Although he had decided weeks before to issue a proclamation, he argued with the delegates on September 13th as if it were undecided. In actuality, the problem of emancipation was one of timing. If emancipation came too soon, support for the war might lessen and the south win. In any event, slavery would have been extended throughout the north.]]></description><link>https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-125qcs6p/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-125qcs6p/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 1968 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://mith-uta.s3.amazonaws.com/data/audio/cpb-aacip-500-125qcs6p.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mp3"/><dc:creator>Northern Illinois University</dc:creator><dc:subject>United States--Politics and government--19th century</dc:subject></item><item><title><![CDATA[Freedom Fighter, 1860]]></title><description><![CDATA[Episode 5: On February 27, 1860, Lincoln again proved his vision in the struggle for racial equality. Lincoln responded to an invitation from the Young Men's Republican Union to speak to a crowd of distinguished listeners at the Cooper Institute in New York. In the speech, he carefully documented his assertion that the framers of the Constitution had out of necessity tolerated slavery but had eagerly anticipated the time when it would no longer blight the nation’s name.]]></description><link>https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-ks6j544n/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-ks6j544n/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 1968 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://mith-uta.s3.amazonaws.com/data/audio/cpb-aacip-500-ks6j544n.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mp3"/><dc:creator>Northern Illinois University</dc:creator><dc:subject>United States--Politics and government--19th century</dc:subject></item><item><title><![CDATA[And What of Religion?]]></title><description><![CDATA[Episode 9: What about Abraham Lincoln's religion? Is his religion a myth or did he blossom into a leader any religious institution would be proud to call their own? This program provides evidence of Lincoln's faith through a careful examination of the highlights of his life.]]></description><link>https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-0v89m70b/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-0v89m70b/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 1968 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://mith-uta.s3.amazonaws.com/data/audio/cpb-aacip-500-0v89m70b.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mp3"/><dc:creator>Northern Illinois University</dc:creator><dc:subject>United States--History--19th century</dc:subject></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Key to the Future of Agriculture]]></title><description><![CDATA[Episode 3: Today's reading: the key to the future of agriculture. On September 30th, 1859, Abraham Lincoln gave the world another opportunity to hear his prophetic words, this time in the area of agriculture. What is particularly impressive is his insistence on the need for the farmer to continue in education--for example, reading--and to continue in joining of hands with science. Science and education then are the key to the future of agriculture, according to Lincoln.]]></description><link>https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-gb1xj48h/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-gb1xj48h/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 1968 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://mith-uta.s3.amazonaws.com/data/audio/cpb-aacip-500-gb1xj48h.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mp3"/><dc:creator>Northern Illinois University</dc:creator><dc:subject>Wisconsin</dc:subject></item></channel></rss>