<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[The comic arts II]]></title><description><![CDATA[Essays and interviews on the nature and scope of humor in America. Program consultant for the series: George Q. Lewis of the Humor Societies of America.<br /><br />An online collection of early educational public radio content from the National Association of Educational Broadcasters (NAEB).]]></description><link>https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/programs/the-comic-arts-ii/</link><image><url>https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/images/podcast.png</url><title>The comic arts II</title><link>https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/programs/the-comic-arts-ii/</link></image><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 17:35:36 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/rss/the-comic-arts-ii.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><managingEditor><![CDATA[National Association of Educational Broadcasters]]></managingEditor><item><title><![CDATA[Earl Wilson: Very friendly to comedy]]></title><description><![CDATA[It's hard to get a perspective on an area with as much diversity as the comedy business. But there is a point of reference in the person of the entertainment pundit, the column writer whose beat is the glittering glamorous dynamic Broadway scene, where stars meet audiences over the footlights, where neophytes try for the big break around Manhattan's showcase circuit. Certainly we have one of the leading authorities on humor and entertainment in general in the United States in leading Broadway columnist Earl Wilson.]]></description><link>https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-wp9t5x6d/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-wp9t5x6d/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 1968 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://mith-uta.s3.amazonaws.com/data/audio/cpb-aacip-500-wp9t5x6d.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mp3"/><dc:creator>Michigan State University</dc:creator><dc:subject>Wit and humor</dc:subject></item><item><title><![CDATA[A top banana: He knows where the laughs are]]></title><description><![CDATA[Even after years of toil in the difficult art of comedy, you remain exposed to the whims of fickle fortune. You continue, perplexed by the vagaries of humor and its capricious nature. But you have decided you will sail these uncharted waters and hope to reach landfall amidst waves of laughter. If you would serve the comic muse bravely, you breast the rising tide if you would become a top banana. Your voice would ring with confident pride.]]></description><link>https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-804xmt8d/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-804xmt8d/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 1968 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://mith-uta.s3.amazonaws.com/data/audio/cpb-aacip-500-804xmt8d.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mp3"/><dc:creator>Michigan State University</dc:creator><dc:subject>Wit and humor</dc:subject></item><item><title><![CDATA[Chuck McCann: Longevity is the important thing]]></title><description><![CDATA[It is proverbial that practice makes perfect and most comedians hold the firm conviction This is especially true in the realm of comedy: not only practice but long and thorough exposure and experimentation are fundamental requirements. Chuck McCann, a television comic  well-known in the New YorkCity, area has been working his way steadily along towards the national spotlight but only when he is sure that he has absorbed enough of the seasoning and experience which the art of comedy demands.]]></description><link>https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-j09w5015/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-j09w5015/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 1968 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://mith-uta.s3.amazonaws.com/data/audio/cpb-aacip-500-j09w5015.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mp3"/><dc:creator>Michigan State University</dc:creator><dc:subject>Wit and humor</dc:subject></item><item><title><![CDATA[Sam Levenson: I told jokes naturally]]></title><description><![CDATA[There is no comedian in America today who better carries on the traditional folk humor of Mark Twain or Will Rogers than Sam Levenson, teacher-turned-performer trading the blackboard and pointer for stage lights and a microphone. Now he may well boast a classroom of millions of Americans. He shares with us a moment of truth that is sometimes painful but always humorous. As Mr. Levinson tells his stories on stage, we nod and smile at recalling a shared experience, be that broken arm or the family picnic. Or maybe that unforgettable first day of school.]]></description><link>https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-8k74zj69/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-8k74zj69/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 1968 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://mith-uta.s3.amazonaws.com/data/audio/cpb-aacip-500-8k74zj69.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mp3"/><dc:creator>Michigan State University</dc:creator><dc:subject>Wit and humor</dc:subject></item><item><title><![CDATA[Jack E. Leonard: Good evening, opponents]]></title><description><![CDATA[Few actors can consistently employ the pointed insult as their stock in trade and get in return not resentment but peals of delighted laughter consistently employ the pointed insult as their stock in trade and get in return not resentment but peals of delighted laughter. Even more rare is the performer who can parlay such ability into a big time career complete with the rewards of fame and fortune. Among the few who have done this is an entertainer who enjoys a unique image and as well that most sincere form of flattery: imitation. We interviewed the great nightclub and television comedian Jackie Leonard for the comic art series.]]></description><link>https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-vt1gp991/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-vt1gp991/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 1968 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://mith-uta.s3.amazonaws.com/data/audio/cpb-aacip-500-vt1gp991.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mp3"/><dc:creator>Michigan State University</dc:creator><dc:subject>Wit and humor</dc:subject></item><item><title><![CDATA[Bob Orben: Twenty-five jokes a day]]></title><description><![CDATA[The author of a volume titled The Joke Teller's Handbook has to be a special sort of writer and he certainly is. He's known around the world as the source of a prodigious amount of topical humor which is the staple of modern comedy diets. Behind the name is a prolific writer who disciplines himself to a tough daily grind at the typewriter who has published more than 40 books of comedy material.]]></description><link>https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-s17ssb28/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-s17ssb28/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 1968 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://mith-uta.s3.amazonaws.com/data/audio/cpb-aacip-500-s17ssb28.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mp3"/><dc:creator>Michigan State University</dc:creator><dc:subject>Wit and humor</dc:subject></item><item><title><![CDATA[Joan Rivers: Everything really happens]]></title><description><![CDATA[One of the most delightful personalities on America's contemporary comedy scene is comedienne Joan Rivers. her comic style is both charming and feminine as well as funny. It is moreover based on genuine individual experience and viewpoint. As Joan herself explains it, "Funny things just happened to me." Joan's show business story follows a typical pattern: many hard years of obscure experience, then a breakthrough to fame and stardom in early 1965.]]></description><link>https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-hq3s050g/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-hq3s050g/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 1968 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://mith-uta.s3.amazonaws.com/data/audio/cpb-aacip-500-hq3s050g.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mp3"/><dc:creator>Michigan State University</dc:creator><dc:subject>Women</dc:subject></item><item><title><![CDATA[Henny Youngman: Six minutes to make good]]></title><description><![CDATA[When a comic has established a truly unique style in his performing work, he has built the basic foundation for professional progress and audience recognition. Whether they call it the hook, point of view style, or attitude, all comedians are keenly aware of the image factor. An outstanding example of this essential element is the long-term and consistent comedy style of Henny Youngman, the king of the one liners. Armed only with a supply of short sharp jokes and his famous violin, he has successfully occupied a special spot on the show business scene for many years.]]></description><link>https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-8s4jr34v/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-8s4jr34v/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 1968 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://mith-uta.s3.amazonaws.com/data/audio/cpb-aacip-500-8s4jr34v.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mp3"/><dc:creator>Michigan State University</dc:creator><dc:subject>Wit and humor</dc:subject></item><item><title><![CDATA[George Q. Lewis: Did you make someone laugh today?]]></title><description><![CDATA[If there is any one man in America who is concerned day and night with a national sense of humor and its condition, that man is George T. Lewis. He is founder and director of an extensive complex of humor-oriented organizations, including the Humor Exchange Network, the National Association of Gag Writers, and the New York Comedy Workshop. He specializes exclusively in the promotion and development of humor- related activities and his motto is, "Did you make someone laugh today?"]]></description><link>https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-mp4vnq1q/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-mp4vnq1q/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 1968 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://mith-uta.s3.amazonaws.com/data/audio/cpb-aacip-500-mp4vnq1q.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mp3"/><dc:creator>Michigan State University</dc:creator><dc:subject>Wit and humor</dc:subject></item><item><title><![CDATA[Danny Thomas: There are no overnight stars]]></title><description><![CDATA[Danny Thomas has enjoyed many years of popularity as a cafe, theatre, and television performer and topped off his career as a star with outstanding success as a producer. He is a brilliant show business man who knows the entertainment field from the ground up all the way to the top. He is also a generous man who gives a lot of his personal time to help others including younger performers seeking advice and counsel.]]></description><link>https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-mp4vnq9n/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-mp4vnq9n/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 1968 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://mith-uta.s3.amazonaws.com/data/audio/cpb-aacip-500-mp4vnq9n.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mp3"/><dc:creator>Michigan State University</dc:creator><dc:subject>Wit and humor</dc:subject></item><item><title><![CDATA[Harold Lloyd: The golden silents]]></title><description><![CDATA[In the mid 1960s, a man who won fame in the 20s and 30s revisited the entertainment scene. Harold Lloyd, the great comedian of the early movies, came around to college towns with a reissue of films from the era of the Golden Silents. He found a brand new audience a new generation of film fans eager to hear about his work in the slapstick days. Harold Lloyd explains the reception given his vintage film the freshman by modern moviegoers. ]]></description><link>https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-pn8xfg5w/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-pn8xfg5w/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 1968 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://mith-uta.s3.amazonaws.com/data/audio/cpb-aacip-500-pn8xfg5w.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mp3"/><dc:creator>Michigan State University</dc:creator><dc:subject>Wit and humor</dc:subject></item><item><title><![CDATA[H. Allen Smith: Thirty books on a totem pole]]></title><description><![CDATA[This speaker is H. Allen Smith, author of several dozen books of humor. He tells a story or spins a yarn somewhat in the way grandpa used to do. His specialty: the written word. His beginning: as a feature writer with a New York newspaper thirty years ago.]]></description><link>https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-0g3h2259/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-0g3h2259/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 1968 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://mith-uta.s3.amazonaws.com/data/audio/cpb-aacip-500-0g3h2259.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mp3"/><dc:creator>Michigan State University</dc:creator><dc:subject>Wit and humor</dc:subject></item><item><title><![CDATA[Art Buchwald: Something bugs me every day]]></title><description><![CDATA[Our subject today is humor in print: the work of the humorous writer, the world as reflected in the words from his pen. Our guest is Art Buchwald. The internationally syndicated columnist author of several very popular humor books is famous today not only as a writer but as a public speaker, commentator, and entertainer.]]></description><link>https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-nz80qf5x/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-nz80qf5x/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 1968 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://mith-uta.s3.amazonaws.com/data/audio/cpb-aacip-500-nz80qf5x.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mp3"/><dc:creator>Michigan State University</dc:creator><dc:subject>Wit and humor</dc:subject></item></channel></rss>