<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[What must be done]]></title><description><![CDATA[This series takes as its point of departure the award-winning issue of Newsweek Magazine published on November 20, 1967: "The Negro in America, What Must Be Done, a Program for Action." Moderated by Manhattan Borough president Percy Sutton, it features discussions about potential solutions to problems affecting ghettos, urban areas, and race relations.<br /><br />An online collection of early educational public radio content from the National Association of Educational Broadcasters (NAEB).]]></description><link>https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/programs/what-must-be-done/</link><image><url>https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/images/podcast.png</url><title>What must be done</title><link>https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/programs/what-must-be-done/</link></image><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 17:35:36 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/rss/what-must-be-done.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><managingEditor><![CDATA[National Association of Educational Broadcasters]]></managingEditor><item><title><![CDATA[Housing]]></title><description><![CDATA[The 1967 Newsweek article established three interrelated issues affecting inner city residents: education, employment, and housing. Discussing the housing issue are Osborn Elliott; H. Ralph Taylor, assistant secretary of the U.S. Department. of Housing and Urban Development; Thomas F. Murray, vice president, Equitable Insurance Company.; Dr. Frank Horne, assistant administrator for equal opportunities, New York City Housing and Development; and Mr. Jack F. Wood, Jr. executive co-director of the National Committee against Discrimination in Housing.]]></description><link>https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-kh0f0858/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-kh0f0858/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 1968 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://mith-uta.s3.amazonaws.com/data/audio/cpb-aacip-500-kh0f0858.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mp3"/><dc:creator>WLIB (Radio station : New York, N.Y.)</dc:creator><dc:subject>U.S. Government</dc:subject></item><item><title><![CDATA[Employment, Part 2]]></title><description><![CDATA[This program, a continuation of the previous episode, addresses what is possibly the most critical of all of the problems of the ghetto: employment. It goes beyond mere statistics of the number of people working unemployed, covering such things as the kind of jobs available to people and the income earned. Guests: Arjay Miller, vice chairman, Ford Motor Company.; Don Slaiman, director, Civil Rights Department., AFL-CIO; and Cyril Tyson, chairman, New York City Human Resources Administration.]]></description><link>https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-542jbh7c/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-542jbh7c/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 1968 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://mith-uta.s3.amazonaws.com/data/audio/cpb-aacip-500-542jbh7c.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mp3"/><dc:creator>WLIB (Radio station : New York, N.Y.)</dc:creator><dc:subject>Wages</dc:subject></item><item><title><![CDATA[White Racism and Black Nationalism]]></title><description><![CDATA[A conversation about movements toward black nationalism and black separatism as well as white America's lack of understanding about their driving influences. Panelists: Osborn Elliott, editor of Newsweek; Whitney Young, Jr., executive director, National Urban League; Floyd McKissick, national director, Congress of Racial Equality (CORE).]]></description><link>https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-mp4vnq75/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-mp4vnq75/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 1968 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://mith-uta.s3.amazonaws.com/data/audio/cpb-aacip-500-mp4vnq75.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mp3"/><dc:creator>WLIB (Radio station : New York, N.Y.)</dc:creator><dc:subject>United States--Race relations</dc:subject></item><item><title><![CDATA[Health]]></title><description><![CDATA[This program examines the physical and mental health issues affecting African Americans, the difficulties involved with getting medical care in the inner cities and rural areas, and African American physicians' exclusion from medical associations and groups. Panelists: Osborn Elliott, editor, Newsweek; Dr. John L.S. Holloman, American Medical Association; Dr. James Haughton, New York City Health Services Administration; Dr. Alvin Poussaint, Tufts University.]]></description><link>https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-xp6v2s6x/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-xp6v2s6x/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 1968 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://mith-uta.s3.amazonaws.com/data/audio/cpb-aacip-500-xp6v2s6x.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mp3"/><dc:creator>WLIB (Radio station : New York, N.Y.)</dc:creator><dc:subject>Sociology</dc:subject></item><item><title><![CDATA[The National Commitment]]></title><description><![CDATA[In the final program, panelists discussed the current lack of commitment--in the U.S. Congress, state and local governments, the private sector, and among the American people--to solving the education, employment, and housing problems of the inner city ghettos. Guests: John V. Lindsay, mayor of New York City; Whitney Young, Jr., executive director, National Urban League; Floyd McKissick, national director, Congress of Racial Equality (CORE); and Osborn Elliott, editor of Newsweek.]]></description><link>https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-z02z7m8w/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-z02z7m8w/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 1968 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://mith-uta.s3.amazonaws.com/data/audio/cpb-aacip-500-z02z7m8w.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mp3"/><dc:creator>WLIB (Radio station : New York, N.Y.)</dc:creator><dc:subject>United States--Politics and government--20th century</dc:subject></item><item><title><![CDATA[Money Sources]]></title><description><![CDATA[In this program--a continuation of the previous episode--panelists discuss the need for a reordering of national budgetary priorities to support inner city problems in light of the enormous strain of funding the Vietnam War. Guests: Newsweek editor Osborn Elliott; futurist/economist Robert Theobald; educator and human rights activist Dr. Vivian Henderson, president, Clark College of Atlanta; and Dr. Dick Netzer, municipal finance expert at New York University.]]></description><link>https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-x63b4b67/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-x63b4b67/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 1968 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://mith-uta.s3.amazonaws.com/data/audio/cpb-aacip-500-x63b4b67.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mp3"/><dc:creator>WLIB (Radio station : New York, N.Y.)</dc:creator><dc:subject>War &amp; Civil Defense</dc:subject></item><item><title><![CDATA[Black-White Relations Today]]></title><description><![CDATA[The series opened with a discussion of black-white relations, with comments by Newsweek editor Osborn Elliott, black power advocate Dr. Nathan Wright, Congress of Racial Equality founder James Farmer, and New York City assistant chief inspector Eldridge Waith.]]></description><link>https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-3f4kqn48/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-3f4kqn48/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 1968 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://mith-uta.s3.amazonaws.com/data/audio/cpb-aacip-500-3f4kqn48.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mp3"/><dc:creator>WLIB (Radio station : New York, N.Y.)</dc:creator><dc:subject>U.S. History (1900-present)</dc:subject></item><item><title><![CDATA[Self-Help]]></title><description><![CDATA[Among the bitter attitudes and ideologies swirling through the black communities, at least one notion strikes a powerful chord of concurrence: above all African Americans want control of their own destinies. Self help has a great deal to do with control of one's own destiny and a simple matter of human pride. Newsweek editor Osborn Elliott; Berkeley G. Burrell, president of the National Business League of Washington, D.C. Elmer Young, Jr., administrative executive of the Opportunities Industrialization Center; and Raymond Brown, vice president of the Freedom National Bank, New York, discuss the matter.]]></description><link>https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-vd6p463q/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-vd6p463q/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 1968 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://mith-uta.s3.amazonaws.com/data/audio/cpb-aacip-500-vd6p463q.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mp3"/><dc:creator>WLIB (Radio station : New York, N.Y.)</dc:creator><dc:subject>Sociology</dc:subject></item><item><title><![CDATA[Money Sources]]></title><description><![CDATA[In this program, panelists discussed the need for a reordering of national budgetary priorities to support inner city problems in light of the enormous strain of funding the Vietnam War. Guests: Newsweek editor Osborn Elliott; futurist/economist Robert Theobald; educator and human rights activist Dr. Vivian Henderson, president, Clark College of Atlanta; and Dr. Dick Netzer, municipal finance expert at New York University.]]></description><link>https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-br8mhv0x/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-br8mhv0x/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 1968 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://mith-uta.s3.amazonaws.com/data/audio/cpb-aacip-500-br8mhv0x.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mp3"/><dc:creator>WLIB (Radio station : New York, N.Y.)</dc:creator><dc:subject>War &amp; Civil Defense</dc:subject></item><item><title><![CDATA[Employment, Part 1]]></title><description><![CDATA[This program addresses what is possibly the most critical of all of the problems of the ghetto: employment. It goes beyond mere statistics of the number of people working unemployed, covering such things as the kind of jobs available to people and the income earned. Guests: Arjay Miller, vice chairman, Ford Motor Company.; Don Slaiman, director, Civil Rights Department., AFL-CIO; and Cyril Tyson, chairman, New York City Human Resources Administration.]]></description><link>https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-3775z32x/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-3775z32x/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 1968 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://mith-uta.s3.amazonaws.com/data/audio/cpb-aacip-500-3775z32x.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mp3"/><dc:creator>WLIB (Radio station : New York, N.Y.)</dc:creator><dc:subject>Wages</dc:subject></item><item><title><![CDATA[Education, Part 1]]></title><description><![CDATA[A panel discussion on the importance of a high quality education to inner city students with Osborn Elliott, editor of Newsweek magazine; Jonathan Kozol, teacher, writer, and specialist on ghetto schools; and Dr. Elliott Shapiro, New York City District 3 school superintendent with the New York City Board of Education.]]></description><link>https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-222r8m9q/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-222r8m9q/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 1968 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://mith-uta.s3.amazonaws.com/data/audio/cpb-aacip-500-222r8m9q.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mp3"/><dc:creator>WLIB (Radio station : New York, N.Y.)</dc:creator><dc:subject>Youth</dc:subject></item><item><title><![CDATA[Aid for the Needy]]></title><description><![CDATA[More than 40 percent of the nation's 22 million African Americans are officially classed as poor, and of these 9.6 million people only a third are receiving help of any kind. This program examined the importance of reducing urban poverty, including addressing the inequitable national welfare system. Panelists: Osborn Elliott, editor of Newsweek; Major Owens, commissioner of the Community Development Agency, New York City Human Resources Administration; Dr. George Wylie, executive director; National Welfare Rights Organization of Washington D.C.; and Dr. Lylse Carter, deputy director of the National Urban Coalition,  Washington D.C.]]></description><link>https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-b853kd3z/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-b853kd3z/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 1968 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://mith-uta.s3.amazonaws.com/data/audio/cpb-aacip-500-b853kd3z.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mp3"/><dc:creator>WLIB (Radio station : New York, N.Y.)</dc:creator><dc:subject>U.S. Government</dc:subject></item><item><title><![CDATA[Education, Part 2]]></title><description><![CDATA[A continuation of a panel discussion on the importance of a high quality education to inner city students with Osborn Elliott, editor of Newsweek magazine; Jonathan Kozol, teacher, writer, and specialist on ghetto schools; and Dr. Elliott Shapiro, New York City District 3 school superintendent with the New York City Board of Education.]]></description><link>https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-zw18r68x/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.unlockingtheairwaves.org/episode/cpb-aacip-500-zw18r68x/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 1968 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://mith-uta.s3.amazonaws.com/data/audio/cpb-aacip-500-zw18r68x.mp3" length="0" type="audio/mp3"/><dc:creator>WLIB (Radio station : New York, N.Y.)</dc:creator><dc:subject>Youth</dc:subject></item></channel></rss>